Gabriel Medina Software Engineer

22564 Tijuana, México

+52 664-444-7589 (Mex)

StackOverFlow

gr31ml93@gmail.com

LinkedIn

GitHub



PROFILE

Software Developer with 5+ years of experience in the whole SD Lifecycle. I'm a fast learner and I like to learn different technologies to know the best tool for the job. I'm creative and I can think out of the box. I tend to find practical solutions to problems and avoid over-engineering them. I'm very committed to the projects I work on, I deliver on time and with quality. I wish to get certified in the technologies I work with which will allow me to tackle problems in the best way possible.

"Goals are dreams with deadlines."

- Diana Scharf

EDUCATION

Computer Systems Engineer, UNIDEP ☑

• Best website design award in web class

• Wrote paper for affordable surveillance system

2014 - 2018

Tijuana, México

LANGUAGES

Spanish

English

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Sr., Quickpass Cybersecurity

Working as a full-stack developer, with a wide variety of technologies, creating apps, implementations, and services required for company products

Home Office | Tijuana,

- Worked in a password management app used by IT assistance companies
- Migrated app from WPF to WIN UI 3
- Created an app auto-update service and logic to keep app updated
- Integrated SSO functionality with different service providers
- Researched and implemented MSIX Installer technology

Software Developer (Mid.), EPAM Systems □

Working as a full-stack developer, in the banking area, mainly in data interpretation, communicating apps, XML and ISON formating

• Helped in the creation, design, and improvement of a developer API testing tools for internal usage

Fullstack Developer, Unosquare

Participated in the Center of Excellence improving my skills in: Vanilla Javascript, Design Patterns, Angular Production Level and Entity Framework, Unit Testing with Jazmine

Fullstack Developer, Advancio

Worked in a variety of projects both in the frontend and the backend in Insurance companies, learning platforms and courier services. I served as the BA and developer for one of the projects. Technologies used include: .netcore, Angular, Google APIs for location, AWS.

- Researched and implemented a video streaming service that relied on AWS authentication.
- Served as the de-facto lead for one of the teams and collaborated with UI/UX designers and testers to deliver a quality product.

Fullstack Developer, Farmacia Roma

Worked as a full-stack developer for multiple projects. Created new features and maintenance for legacy systems as well as created new applications with Xamarin. Developed integrations to SAP. Created the backend for an application for delivery of products to customers' homes

- Served as a mentor for 4 developers who used to work with legacy platforms, teaching them web development and web architecture.
- Research and Development for purchasing the best cost-benefit device used for the reception of merchandise in the pharmacy's branches.
- Improved and updated the device Kernel, reducing issues with scanning.

2022-08 - 2024-04

México

2021-12 - 2022-08

Home Office | Tijuana, Mexico

2021-08 - 2021-12

Home Office | Tijuana, México

2020-10 - 2021-08

Home Office | Tijuana, México

2018-05 - 2020-10

Tijuana, México

SKILLS .NetCore | ASP | C# VS Code / Visual Studio Entity Framework JavaScript | TypeScript HTML CSS | SASS Angular 2+ Angular Material NgRx | RxJS Node.JS SQL MongoDB / Atlas Design Patterns GIT/Bitbucket Sonar Qube Azure CI/CD

• • • •

• • • •

Sonar Qube		Azure CI/CD
Unit Testing (Jazmine)	\bullet \bullet \circ \circ	WIN UI 3
Docker	\bullet \bullet \circ \circ	WSL / Ubuntu
XAML	\bullet \bullet \circ \circ	Postman
RESTful API	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$	GIT / Bitbucket
LINQ / Lambda	• • • • •	MVVM
Web2View	\bullet \bullet \circ \circ	Jira
SCRUM	• • • • •	GCP (Buckets)
SSO Integrations	\bullet \bullet \circ \circ	Google Geolocation Services
NGRok	\bullet \bullet \circ \circ	WLS
React.Js	• • • • •	Docker
WinUI3	• • • • •	Dependency Injection

YML

Powershell